所以这是一个非常强大的验证库的开始，我们
So this is the beginning of a pretty, pretty strong validation library that we
可以做得更好，我们正在使用失败和成功。
can make better, and we're using fail and success.
我想对这个库做最后一件事，只是为了让它更酷一点。
I want to do one last thing to this library, just to make it a little cooler.
我们想说，而不是仅仅连接结果。
Is we wanna say, instead of just concatenating the results.
我们实际上可以连接整个验证本身。
We could actually concat the entire validation itself.
现在，我可以在这里做出几个决定。
Now, I can make a couple decisions here.
我可以对此进行验证。
I can put a validation around this.
所以我必须有一些东西可以组合，对吗？
So I have to have something to combine, right?
因此，我不仅拥有一个函数，还拥有一个保存该函数的验证。
So instead of just having a function, I have a validation holding the function.
现在我可以将这些东西结合起来。
And now I can combine these things.
所以这是我可以做出的一个决定。
So that's one decision I can make.
另一种可能是，
Another one could be,
我可以要求这个函数返回成功或失败。
I can demand that this function return me a success or a failure.
所以我可以说，好吧，让我们去做，如果它真的在那里，我们会留住你，
So I can say well, all right, let's do, if it's actually there, we'll keep you,
否则，我们会看到你失败。
otherwise, we'll see you a failure.
现在我实际上可以嵌入一条消息，而不仅仅是关键是坏的，对吧？
And now I can actually embed a message instead of just key is bad, right?
我可以做一个消息说，
And I can do a message saying,
需要在场，对吗？
needs to be present, right?
所以这很好，但是，我们在这里错过了关键。
So that's nice, but then, we're missing the key here.
所以这些是我现在正在考虑我的选择做出决定的事情。
So these are things I'm making decisions right now considering my options.
所以，我想我要做什么，假设验证需要一个密钥，然后
So, I think what I'm gonna do, let's say a validation takes in a key and
一个 x，我们就可以说，构造我们的消息，说这里的关键。
an x, and we're gonna be able to say, construct our message saying the key here.
然后，我们可以使用 x 运行我们的验证。
And then, we can run our validation with the x.
这就是我要定义的验证的形式。
So this is the shape of a validation that I'm going to define.
这有点具有一些架构含义。
And that kinda has some architectural implications.
还要注意我把它放在一个数组中。
Notice also I'm putting this in an array.
因为我不会无法连接它所持有的任何东西，
Because I just won't fail to concat whatever it's holding,
我可以连接一堆字符串，这仍然有效。
I can concat a bunch of strings, that still works.
但是然后我需要在这里有这些空间以使其看起来不错并且
But then I would need to have these spaces in here to make it look nice and
我只是有一系列的结果，太酷了。
I just rather have an array of results, so cool.
所以我们现在可以去创建一个验证幺半群，让我们开始吧。
So we can go make a validation monoid now, let's go.
所以我们有两件事要做，我们必须做一个验证幺半群和
So we have two things to do, we have to do a validation monoid and
我们必须在那里更新这个缓慢的小部分。
we have to update this little slow part down there.
所以，这里发生的事情是我们可以在这里运行验证。
So, what's happening here is we could run the validation right here.
但这不再是一个功能，对吧？
But that's no longer a function, right?
这将是一个验证函数，验证对象。
It's gonna be a validation function, validation object.
所以我们会给它一个run方法，run。
So we'll give that a run method, run.
然后这将使我成功或失败。
And then that will return me a success or a fail.
所以我实际上可以摆脱它，对吧。
So I could actually just get rid of that, right.
我告诉它我会给它一个键和值。
And I told it that I would give it a key and the value.
所以这很不错。
So that's pretty nice.
每个人都看到它是如何工作的吗？
Does everybody see how that works?
我还没有进行验证，但这就是我正在绘制的草图，
I haven't made validation yet, but this is kind of what I'm sketching out to make,
是验证将返回成功或失败。
is that validation will return me a success or a failure.
当我运行验证时，我可能会结合一堆验证
And when I run the validation, I'm gonna combine a bunch of validations by probably
有效地将他们的失败结合起来。
effectively combining their failures underneath.
这给了我结合的能力。
And this gives me the ability to combine.
这现在与一个可能的 concat isEmail 一起出现。
This is present now with a maybe concat isEmail.
所以让我们继续写这篇文章。
So let's go ahead and get through writing this.
因此，使用 isPresent 进行一些简单的邮件验证，并且
So make a little easy mail validation to go along with isPresent, and
让我们做与 isEmail 完全相同的事情，哎呀，
let's do the exact same thing like isEmail, whoops,
isEmail 将是一个验证，我们只会说像 x。
isEmail will be a validation, we'll just say like x.
关于 testX，我们去了[笑]。
About at testX, there we go [LAUGH].
所以如果它有一个加号，我们就会相信这是一封电子邮件，
So if it has an add sign, we'll believe it's an email,
否则必须是电子邮件，很酷。
otherwise must be an email, cool.
让我们继续编写验证，所以
And let's go ahead and write validation, so
我们会在这里做，常量验证。
we'll do that up here, const validation.
这需要一个 F。
That takes an F.
我们将称之为跑步，所以我们可以进行下注，我们会说跑步。
We'll just call that run, so we can do punting, we'll say run.
是的，如果我要结合两个验证，我们会说好，
Right, and if I was gonna combine two validations, we'll say well,
总是会返回一个新的验证。
were always gonna return a new validation.
该验证需要一个密钥和一个 x，然后我们将运行。
That validation takes a key, and an x, and we'll run.
让我们看看，我们将对密钥和 x 进行验证。
Let's see, we'll run our validation on the key and the x.
我们将连接失败或成功的结果
And we'll concat the result which is going to be a fail or a success with
运行其他人的结果，或对 x 中的键进行其他验证。
the result of running the others, or the other validation on the key in the x.
多么酷啊？
How cool is that?
[笑]所以我们在这里做的是说，
[LAUGH] so what we're doing here is saying,
我们有这个验证，我们可以与其他验证结合起来，
we have this validation that we can combine altogether with other validations,
当我们运行它时，它会运行所有这些。
and when we run it, it's gonna run all of them.
它会结合所有的结果 他们会结合他们的结果
And it's gonna combine all the results and they're gonna combine their results and
[听不清] 等等。
[INAUDIBLE] so on, etc.
让我们看看这是否有效，我确定我会遇到错误。
Let's see if this works, I'm sure I'm gonna hit a bug.
&gt;&gt; [音频不清晰] 键在您的失败案例中。
&gt;&gt; [INAUDIBLE] key in your fail cases.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢，那在哪儿？
&gt;&gt; Thank you, where is that?
&gt;&gt; IsEmail, &gt;&gt; IsEmail 拿到钥匙,
&gt;&gt; IsEmail, &gt;&gt; IsEmail got the key,
它甚至告诉我，它说你没有使用密钥。
it's even telling me, it say you're not using key.
好吧，很酷，成功可能是一样的，是的，谢谢。
All right, cool, and it's probably the same in success, yeah, thank you.
欣赏第二对 Is。
Appreciate the second pair of Is.
所以让我们看看这是否有效。
So let's see if this works.
我不想花太多时间在上面，好吗？
I don't wanna spend too much time on it, all right?
所以它通过了。让我们摆脱电子邮件。
So it got through that. Let's get rid of the email.
看看能不能熬过去。
See if it gets through that.
电子邮件必须是电子邮件，这是肯定的。
Email must be an email, that's for sure.
如果我把这个拿出来怎么办？
What if I take this out?
姓名需要出现，电子邮件必须是电子邮件，这很酷。
Name needs to be present, email must be email, and this is pretty cool.
如果我做布赖恩，我就完全摆脱了这个。
If I do Brian and I get rid of this altogether.
电子邮件需要存在并且必须是电子邮件才能正常工作。
The email needs to be present and must be an email so it's working.
它运作良好。让我们快速查看一下这段代码
It's working well. Let's just quickly look over this code for
一分钟，看看我们做了什么。
a minute, and see what we've done.
我们实际上可以继续前进。
We can actually keep going.
[笑] 越来越激烈了吧？
[LAUGH] More and more intense, right?
就像如果，一件很有趣的事情是定义
Like what if, one thing that would be fun is to define
一个验证，如果我要合并它。
a validation that is, if I'm gonna combine it.
如果我这样做或[笑]或者这个或那个怎么办，对吧？
What if I do or [LAUGH] Or this or that, right?
或者我可以说，而不是仅仅将它们组合起来，我可以说或
Or alternatively I could say, instead of just combining them I could say or
就在那里，但这不适用于幺半群和
right there, but that wouldn't be working with monoids and
这些知道如何连接东西的抽象接口。
these abstract interfaces that know how to concat stuff.
所以我们可以继续构建它，结果是这样的订单很好。
So we can keep building this up and it turns out and an order form this nice.
它将被称为半环，它们在其中相互作用并
It will be called semi ring where they interact and
相互分配并创建一种非常非常好的表达方式。
distribute over each other and create a really, really nice way to say like.
我将结合所有这些验证，即 AND 和 OR 的混合。
I'm gonna combine all these validations in a way that's, a mixture of ANDs and ORs.
所以我可以说，好吧，如果你给我一封电子邮件以确保它看起来像一封电子邮件，
So I can say, well, if you do give me an email to make sure it looks like an email,
但你不必，对，那种东西。
but you don't have to, right, that kind of stuff.
这也可以变得非常有效。
And that can get really efficient as well.
所以，很酷，在我们按下按钮之前关于验证的任何问题，
So, cool, any questions on validations before we kind of button this up,
我们实际上稍后会使用它，所以让我们继续
we're actually going to use this later so let's go ahead and
只需导出，验证 [笑]。
just export, validate [LAUGH].
哎呀，导出，验证，实际上我想我必须做模块导出续集
Whoops, export, validate and actually I think I have to do module export sequels
因为我们不会使用包之类的。
because we're not gonna be using packages and such.